In this step we're going to sew the pieces of the animal face to the background fabric.
First you're going to need some thread.
Some pins. Scissors. And a needle. And your pieces. So on this we're doing the panda face. I'm first going to take a pin and pin the fabric to the background fabric.
Also, you want to coordinate the color of your thread to what you're sewing.
So right now I'm going to be sewing this black bit on so I want black thread.
When I sew the white bit of the panda's eye on there I'm going to use white thread.
And then when I sew the black pupil of the eye back on I'll use the black thread again.
You just want to keep consistent with the color of the fabric that you're sewing on.
So start with your needle and thread.
I've doubled up the thread.
Knotted it at the end and it's in there.
Go from the bottom up and you're just going to do a running stitch which basically means you go up and down.
Up and down.
You're going to continue this all the way around the perimeter of your object.
Keep the stitches even and there should be an even space between them as well.
When you're done sewing your animal face it should look something like this.
You notice how I used the white thread on the white.
The black thread on the black.
And it's all securely on the base of my animal face.